SARA CHABOT

User Experience Design

SUMMARY

A UX designer with a passion in generating innovative solutions and user-friendly experiences and products across the globe. Known for adaptability, curiosity, and attention to detail. With a background in Interaction Design, I am capable of front-end developing and UX research/Design.

CONTACT

sarachabot.com 571 969 9127 sarachabot13@gmail.com

EDUCATION

IAMES MADISON UNIVERSITY

B.A. in Media Arts and Design **2020-2022**

NORTHERN VIRGINIA COMMUNITY

A.A. in Communication Studies **2018-2020**

Honors: Summa Cum Laude

UX METHOD

Prototyping
Wireframing
Usability Testing
Contextual Inquiry
Data Analysis
Personas/User Stories/User Narratives
Storyboards
Information Architecture

SOFTWARE

Illustrator
InDesign
XD
Photoshop
Premiere Pro
Axure RP
Figma
Visual Studio Code
GitHub

PROGRAMMING

HTML CSS Bootstrap JavaScript

LANGUAGE

Fluent in English Native in Japanese

COURSE WORK

CONVERGED MEDIA LAB

- Designed comprehensive personas, wireframes, functional requirements, and high-fidelity prototype for a client's website
- Led the UX research for a development team of eight and revamped the user flow by implementing user-centered design
- Refined an extensive user research report and style guide for a selfdesigned app

VISUAL COMMUNICATION DESIGN

 Created outdoor signage, typography, logos, and photo framed silhouettes for a local exhibition

INTERACTIVE DESIGN FOR THE WEB-I AND WEB II

- Developed 10 websites by applying CSS and HTML coding and Bootstrap
- Redesigned the user interface by creating an app-flow redesign case study report
- Developed graphics and and statistics using JavaScript

USER INTERACTION DESIGN

- Streamlined the UX design team of five by creating storyboards, comparative analysis, user journey maps, and high-fidelity prototype for an app
- Eliminated design errors and maximized the efficiency of the app by conducting usability testing

WORK EXPERIENCE

COFFEE PROFESSIONAL

Slipstream (Washington D.C.)

June 2022 – August 2022

- Conducted point of sales, espresso dialing, beverage crafting, light food preparation, and cleaning tasks
- Accurately and promptly took customer's order and answered questions over the phone and in-person

BARISTA TRAINER/BARISTA

Starbucks Coffee Company (Alexandria, VA)

June 2018 - August 20

- Trained new employees about company values, beverage crafting, food safety, and hygiene protocols
- Managed food and beverage preparations while assisting the customer's needs in a fast paced work environment

DESIGN INTERN (REMOTE)

Stable and Wise (Sydney, Australia)

May 2021 - August 2021

- Designed and published two Kindle eBooks for the company
- Improved SEO by editing content for the blog and social media posts, eBooks, and meta data